<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Karl Paragua]]></title>
  <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-19T23:25:39+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[kbparagua]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Palmar Hyperhidrosis]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/palmar-hyperhidrosis/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-19T00:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/palmar-hyperhidrosis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again, I stare at the chessboard.
I can see colored wooden men standing on black and white squares.
Everything is clear, but nothing makes any sense.
Fuck. Here it is again. My heart is pounding so hard. My hands are shaking.
What is happening? My mind is full of shit.</p>

<p>With full of conviction, he moves his piece.</p>

<p>Just what the fuck is that?!
What should I do? Fuck. Fuck. Fuck. I don&rsquo;t know!</p>

<p>I move my piece somewhere. I have no idea. Then instantly, he responds.
As if he already knows what&rsquo;s going to happen next.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Checkmate!&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Ww&mdash;&ndash; what?!&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Before the helpless me even grasps the brutality of the situation, the game ends.
In a snap of a finger, the shaking and pounding is gone.
The gears inside my head starts working again, and then, everything in front of me becomes vivid and obvious.
I see, the black king is helplessly cornered by a single ambitious pawn and of course his powerful racist queen.
What happened? I have no fucking idea. But I know something was wrong during that terrible battle.
It&rsquo;s like that I&rsquo;m not the one who played that game.
All I can recall is my first move, and after that, it seems like someone or something took over the driver&rsquo;s seat for me.
Fuck that.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2196080/chess.jpeg" alt="chess kid" /></p>

<p>Besides torturing my feeble brain through playing chess, I also collect callus through playing guitar.
I play Red Hot Chili Peppers songs almost exclusively.
The frenzy of funky hendirx-esque guitar licks that John Frusciante incorporates in each song are just addicting. Under the Bridge, Snow, Soul to Squeeze, Funky Monks, you name it.
And considering the sublimity of the techniques used in each song,
I absolutely need to practice them slowly until it sounds justifiable.
Applying muscle memory, motor learning, and other scientific buzzwords just to
rationalize my incompetence, I rigorously practice each note transitions up to the
point that my fingers can move without thinking anymore.
But I&rsquo;ve noticed that even how well I can play a song, everything fucks up every time I let my girlfriend listen to me.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I practiced this new funky song! It is cool. Listen.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>With sweaty palms, I hold my cheap black Epiphone Les Paul and assume the <em>i-will-fucking-rock-this-song</em> face. Then one by one, I let the guitar pick slap the strings as they create this alluring funky melody.</p>

<p>A couple of funky notes passed, then all of a sudden the familiar harmony faded.
An off-pitch note was hit. Fuck. A buzzing F chord came next. Fuck again.
My hands begins to shake as I wander across the fretboard looking for the next note.
Great! I forget what&rsquo;s next.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;What the fuck!? Wait. I can do this perfectly during practice! I swear!&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Yeah. That pretty much sums up what happens every time I fucked up playing a Red Hot song.</p>

<p>I guess, you are getting the pattern here.</p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t take a genius to tell that my nerves are kicking in during those fucked up moments. Heart is pounding too fast. Hands are shaking uncontrollably. Mind is going void. We know the symptoms very well. It is clear, I was nervous during those instances, and everyone said that it is certainly normal. But, the big question here is <strong>Why</strong>?</p>

<p>Why the hell am I nervous playing chess?!
A casual game with a friend, without any bets and all the trash-talking.</p>

<p>And please tell me why the fuck is my nerves acting up every time I play a guitar in front of my girlfriend?! My girlfriend of 8 years!</p>

<p>Tell me!</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://kbparagua.github.io//www.youtube.com/embed/81GKi3EIx6U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><em>A short clip showcasing RHCP&rsquo;s orgasmic melody.</em></p>

<p>Mistake is something almost all sane humans cautiously avoid.
But some evade making mistakes faithfully to the point that they developed deep fear with it.
I, for one, is one of those few people, which I came to realize after some time spent staring blankly at our gloomy ceiling. I fear making mistakes, specifically those which can undoubtedly be credited to me. Then, I asked myself, <em>&ldquo;Is it wrong to have this fear?&rdquo;</em>. Just think about it for a moment, mistakes are plainly negative. And I hold my ground that there&rsquo;s no such thing as positive mistake. So it makes a whole lot of sense to avoid it, or even fear it. Why should you love something that is wrong?</p>

<p>Now, here&rsquo;s the other part of the equation. Let&rsquo;s talk about this villain called <em>Fear</em>, particularly fear of making mistakes, and its main weapon <em>nervousness</em>.
This fear hides calmly inside everyone of us, patiently waiting for the right time to unleash nervousness to its prey. And for those who can&rsquo;t tame this beast, just like me,
it will fuck your whole body system without any trace of mercy.
Fear-induced nervousness is unimaginably drastic that it will kill the core of your personality.
Communication, creativity, motor sensors, judgment, everything will be fucked up.
Basically, it is taking over your life for a couple of seconds, and fucking up with everything
you&rsquo;re trying to say, do, or think.</p>

<p>Unlike any other adults, for me, it is perplexing.
Making mistakes and the fear of of them are both negative.
Just what the fuck should I do.
How can I overcome this psychological terror?</p>

<p>So for the next few days before writing the following paragraphs, I&rsquo;ve spent enough time staring on those old ceiling again.
My eyes strolled each cobwebs as if the answers are trapped in them.
I gathered my sanity and logic to come up with a counter-attack, and of course, a reasonable ending for this mediocre article.
After almost reaching the brink of madness, I believe &mdash;&ndash; I wanted to believe that I came up with something.</p>

<p>I missed an important piece of this puzzle, and that is the fact that there are
2 types of mistake. One, is the nasty thing you do after hearing the devil&rsquo;s voice,
and the other is the side effect of some action after an angel&rsquo;s whisper.
And I&rsquo;m so fucking sorry for myself for fearing the latter.</p>

<p><em>Side effect of angel&rsquo;s &mdash;&ndash; what the fuck are you taking about!?</em></p>

<p>Well, those mistakes we make unintentionally from trying to leave our comfort zone.
From trying to learn something new. From trying to be better at something.
From trying to stand up for our principles.
From trying to be creative.
Can we all say that those are not that bad? Really, they are not that grave.
They will not fucking cost you your ticket to heaven.</p>

<p>If you give a second thought about it, maybe there&rsquo;s no serious reason to fear that kind of error.
Maybe it&rsquo;s nature&rsquo;s way of telling you that you are almost at the next level of awesomeness.
Or maybe, it is a gentle reminder that, like the old cliche said, nobody is perfect.
It is a subtle note that reminds us that we, humans, are vulnerable.
That no matter how hard we think, no matter how hard we practice,
we will still find a way to fuck up everything.
Yes, even if we reach the highest level of a specific skill, we will still make blunders from time to time,
or there will still be a 10 year old Asian kid that will be better than us.
So why worry for something that will happen eventually, no matter how hard you try to prevent it?
There&rsquo;s absolutely no reason!</p>

<p>Fuck it.</p>

<p>Fuck the sweaty palms!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sick and Crappy World Of Fitness -- and A Proposed Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/fitness/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-30T01:38:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/fitness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to get straight right away; <strong>The spotlight of physical fitness is your body&rsquo;s health</strong>.
It is not about protein shakes and supplements, neither about <em>P90X</em> nor <em>Crossfit</em>, neither about <em>TRX</em> nor the latest Ab machine. It is about you.</p>

<p>Observing the fitness industry today, I assume that we are losing our focus. Little did we know, we are falling on these clever marketing stunts. Numerous companies are letting us feel that achieving greater fitness is impossible without their product. They also go to the extent that they are proudly announcing that they are revolutionizing the fitness world. So-called <em>&ldquo;Scientific studies&rdquo;</em> are also used to make the stunts more effective. And even worse, the one thing that I hate the most, there are specific organizations that impose themselves as the <strong>enlightened ones</strong>, the <strong>elites</strong>, the <strong>we-are-the-real-meaning-of-fitness</strong>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><a href="http://scoobysworkshop.com/hall-of-shame/">Just look at all these shameful bullshits.</a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not implying that fitness products are not helpful at all. I just feel that the community is already polluted with buzzwords and lies. And considering the pollution&rsquo;s volume, I assure you that lots of beginners are wasting their time doing the wrong things.</p>

<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2196080/funny_chinese_strong_man.jpg" alt="Chinese Strong Man" /></p>

<p>About a year ago, I tried <em>P90X</em>. It was fucking intense and I felt very satisfied with it. For me, it was the best back then. But as adult responsibilities take their places &mdash; <em>fuck it</em>, my time and energy was depleted every single day. I can&rsquo;t even finish a single workout! I became frustrated and eventually stopped.</p>

<p>P90X is a good product, it&rsquo;s just that it&rsquo;s not right for my situation. Then Bruce Lee&rsquo;s wisdom hits me:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;&hellip;be formless, shapeless &mdash; like water&hellip; be water my friend&rdquo;</em>.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Adapt what is useful, reject what is useless, and add what is specifically your own.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><img src="http://maxcdn.zenpencils.com/comics/2012-04-09-bruce-lee-1.jpg" alt="Absorb what is useful" />
<a href="http://zenpencils.com/comic/35-bruce-lee-absorb-what-is-useful/">source</a></p>

<p>Bruce Lee has a valid point. I must adjust. I must experiment. I must create my own style. I must come up with something fit with my own time and energy. So that&rsquo;s what I did. I adjusted P90X in-line with my limitations. I added some concepts from my past experiences. I added exercises I&rsquo;ve learned from my friends. Actually, if you think about it, it&rsquo;s not P90X anymore, rather a <em>custom product tailored specially for me.</em> A <strong>perfect</strong> workout program for me. Up to now, I&rsquo;m constantly adjusting my workouts. I adjust depending on the situation, my body&rsquo;s reaction, time constraint, equipment availability, short-term goal, and other important factors.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s another problem in the fitness world. Sometimes, because of the craze generated by the public media we became too attached to products. We forgot that <strong>there&rsquo;s no silver bullet to obtain physical fitness.</strong> We forgot how to experiment. We forgot to listen to our bodies. We forgot to consider our limitations. We have more to learn. But these marketing stunts and hypes surrounding the fitness world are interfering with our learning. Today, it is very hard to find someone who speaks about fitness without bias or hidden motives.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;You&rsquo;ll be in an amazing shape for just 3 months&hellip; For only $10!&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;We are going to share to you the secret to 6 pack abs for just a gazillion worth of dollars!&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Running is dangerous for your knees. With our product you just need to walk to achieve that sexy body.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Traditional sit-ups might strain your neck and not that efficient at all. Our machine solves that!&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><strong>SHUT. THE. FUCK. UP.</strong></p>

<p>Fitness should be simple. No fancy shits and lies.</p>

<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2196080/the-ultimate-workout.jpg" alt="Simple Workout" /></p>

<p>I want to cut those bullshits. I want a community that has no bias or hidden motives, rather just passion on learning and teaching physical fitness. I strongly believe that we need a community built for the people, not for marketing&rsquo;s sake. Built by the people, not by corporations. We need a community in which there is no authority. In which the authority is the community itself. A community where everyone has a voice on what is right and what is just plain bullshit. And more importantly, <strong>we need a platform to encourage everyone to learn, share, experiment, and discover our own style of physical fitness.</strong></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s why I created <a href="http://www.vanillafit.com">Vanillafit</a>.</p>

<p>No bullshits. No fucking products to shove down your throat. If you feel what I feel, then I must say that this newborn community needs your help.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.vanillafit.com/users/sign_up">Join me in this journey</a>.</p>

<p>Thank you random fitness enthusiast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Whining. We All Have The Same 24 Hours. ]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/08/31/stop-whining-we-all-have-the-same-24-hours/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-31T21:13:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/08/31/stop-whining-we-all-have-the-same-24-hours</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I&rsquo;m paying 10 dollars a year for this blog, and since my brain is beginning to itch with stuff in between shitty and witty, I&rsquo;m obliged to write a fucking article again. Yes, I said <em>fucking</em> without any reason. Deal with it.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m an ambitious procrastinator. Well, I guess most of us are. <strong>Dream big. Do small.</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve many things to do &mdash; suppose to do. But most of my time is spent thinking and stressing about how little time I have to do all those things. You can very well relate I know. We have many things to do. Almost 9 hours in the office, not counting the travel and shitty unnecessary surprise overtimes yet. Then, stupid scientists recommend 8 hours of sleep a day. 8 fucking hours doing nothing! Also, we need to allocate time for eating, peeing, pooping, walking, bathing, house cleaning, and other necessary things ending in <em>ing</em>. I guess an average person is spending at least 19 hours a day to do all his obligations. Then using my cutting edge algebra skills acquired from grade 5, I say that we are only left with 5 hours worth of free time. Not including weekends.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>5 Hours!? Holy Crap! That is not enough to do all my important shits!</strong></p>

<p>If we can only have extra hours on our day. Maybe an extra 5 hours again? Or even another 24 hours? For sure, everyone will be happy. Everyone can finally do the things they&rsquo;ve wanted to do: their hobbies, hanging out with friends, studying, and even sleeping. Ahhh. What a perfect world it can be.</p>

<p>Oh come on! That is fantasy! The reality is that there are only 24 hours a day. Even Chuck Norris has the same number of hours. I&rsquo;ve realized that we are looking at the wrong side of the situation. <strong>Time is not the problem.</strong> It&rsquo;s our attitude towards this precious concept called time. Our constant denial about the fact that time is limited. Our continuous desire to do what is not possible given the time we have. Those are the problems. That&rsquo;s why we are procrastinating. That&rsquo;s why we are depressed. That&rsquo;s why we are frustrated. <strong>Because we can&rsquo;t accept the fact that we truly have 24 hours a day only.</strong> We are fighting an indestructible monster. Let&rsquo;s just accept that it cannot be defeated.</p>

<p><strong>But! A big But!</strong> Errrr. Wait. Maybe I should use <em>however</em>. However! That doesn&rsquo;t mean that we cannot be happy anymore. Just recently, I found out that the rule is simple: Don&rsquo;t try to squeeze tasks into your schedule. Squeezing means that there are no space for it anymore. It will just burn the hell out of you or you will just end up procrastinating and never actually doing it. Leaving you frustrated, depressed, and craving to kill those people who has so much time to tweet every 15 minutes. Rather, <strong>do the tasks that are POSSIBLE with your current supply of time</strong>. And just be contented about it.</p>

<p>You cannot build a plane in an hour. But I&rsquo;m sure you can build many paper planes with that time. I think that can be fun too.</p>

<p><em>&hellip;and it&rsquo;s 1:00 past midnight! If I just have the time to make this article more sensible! Sigh.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lessons After 23 Years]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/lessons-after-23-years/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-14T14:26:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/lessons-after-23-years</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The time has come again to ask myself these disturbing questions:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;So how did you spent your life this year? Anything new? Anything changed? Where are you now?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>I just celebrated either the 23rd year of my mere existence or 23rd year of me living my life. I&rsquo;m still not sure which of the two. Whatever. I&rsquo;ll find out next year. Hopefully. But one thing is for sure, this is the time to stand in front of the mirror and rediscover myself.</p>

<p><em>So, what did you discover looking at your past self? Any lessons for your future self?</em></p>

<p>Okay. I have some minor lessons like <em>Time is Gold</em> or <em>Take a bath everyday</em>, but I&rsquo;ll talk to you about that in another time. For now, here are the 4 major lessons I want you to keep in mind.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>1. Talent is Overrated.</strong></p>

<p>Congratulations! You will do great in school if you are good at something. But after school, well, it&rsquo;s a different playing grounds. We have unthinkable and unimaginable rules here. You can&rsquo;t survive here only with that talent you are bragging about. You will go down fast and early if you hold on to that belief that talent alone will put you on top. The world is a big strategy game. A game of power, deception, and sacrifice. Or in a more concise word, this is <strong>fucking politics</strong> my friend. This is how the world works, you cannot change it. There are only 2 choices: accept and join, or fight and lose.</p>

<p><a href="http://karlparagua.com/blog/2012/12/22/nikola-tesla-is-a-loser/">I&rsquo;ve got to say that I learned this the hard way</a>. After graduating, I spent 2 ore more years depressed and frustrated with myself. Until a friend of mine introduced me to a book called &ldquo;48 Laws of Power&rdquo;. It opened my mind to how this immoral world works. It is bad, yet good. Confusing indeed. Yes, love makes the world go round. But I believe it is specifically pertaining to people&rsquo;s undeniable love for power. It is hard to stomach how this fucking world works. But we have no choice. We can&rsquo;t beat the system. We can&rsquo;t.</p>

<p><strong>2. Direct way is the easiest, but not always the best way.</strong></p>

<p>Honesty is the best policy. Yeah right. Now, tell your boss how much you hate him.</p>

<p>Before, I&rsquo;m a very frank person. I say what I want to say. If I hate you, I will shout it in front of your fucking face. Consequences of my actions are not in my mind. There&rsquo;s nothing in my mind but the overflowing emotion to say how much I want you to die.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t worry. That&rsquo;s all in the past.</p>

<p>Like I&rsquo;ve said, the world is a big strategy game. You need to conceal your emotions if you are playing poker. You need to hide your intentions in chess. You will still pursue your goal, but do it indirectly and with style. Think of a clever way to express your emotion without damaging yourself. Attacking directly is the easiest way, but chances are you will be the in the disadvantaged position in the long run. Use your creativity and attack indirectly.</p>

<p><strong>3. Do something you&rsquo;ve never done to achieve something you never had.</strong></p>

<p>Recently, I had a fight with my girlfriend. It&rsquo;s that kind of fight in which I know that our whole relationship is hanging on the edge. One wrong move and everything will be over. I needed to do something to save our 6-year relationship. But my half-ass attempts to say sorry were not working. Fuck it! So I did what I needed to do. I did something I&rsquo;ve never done in my entire life. I searched for her office, went there early in the morning, gave her flowers, and said I&rsquo;m sorry. That&rsquo;s it. That&rsquo;s my ace. And thanks God, everything went fine. It&rsquo;s a difficult decision for me. I was all nervous and shit. But I needed to do that to achieve her trust again.</p>

<p><strong>It is called stupidity when you do something over and over again, and yet expecting the result to change</strong>. If you can&rsquo;t achieve something after trying countless of times, take a step back and think about that one thing you are afraid to do. Maybe that&rsquo;s the only solution. If you really want to achieve your goals, grow some balls and be willing to do something you haven&rsquo;t done before. Stop thinking about the what-ifs and other shits, just focus on your goal and just do what you need to do!</p>

<p><strong>4. Fear is illogical.</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m afraid of the dark because of those fucking Asian horror movies. Those you-will-question-your-sexuality-after-this movies reveal the little girl inside me (Figuratively!). That&rsquo;s my biggest weakness, and I&rsquo;m not shy about that! However, I really want to destroy that fear inside me. Because I can&rsquo;t be a good father to my future children if I&rsquo;m afraid of the dark. Just think of a dad who can&rsquo;t protect his child against bedroom monsters.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s another secret: I developed an OCD recently.</p>

<p>I will not talk further about the details, but it makes me overthink nonsense things and fear nonsense shits. It was terrible. It ruined my every day life. Until I read about the details of that shitty OCD. Then in that moment, I realized that it is all in the head. It&rsquo;s just my brain playing games with me. The fear is only an illusion. It seems real but if you just take your time to investigate it thoroughly, you will find out that it is just a fake. A beautifully manufactured fake created by your brain to appear super realistic to fool itself. Yes, your brain is fucking with itself.</p>

<p><strong>Your fear is not real</strong>. Think about it. Your mind is the problem, and it is also the solution.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it. Keep these in mind my friend. Good luck to the next year of your life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Fucking Hate You! But We're Good.]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/i-fucking-hate-you-but-were-good/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T17:12:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/i-fucking-hate-you-but-were-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a terrible secret; I sucked at socialization. And I sucked at grammar. <em>Is it really right that I used semicolon there? Is it okay that I started a sentence with an &lsquo;And&rsquo;?</em></p>

<p>Yes, I can talk and hangout with people. But when he/she says or do something bullshit, well fuck, it will be over. That will be the final friendly activity the two of us will have. All remaining encounters will be small hi-hello conversations. I&rsquo;m just so allergic to bullshits, attention whores, know-it-all guys, and all those fucking annoying people I encounter everyday.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Then recently, I asked myself a stupid question: <em>Hey, why do you have too few friends? I mean really close friends.</em></p>

<p>Seriously that is a stupid thing to ask. Obviously It&rsquo;s because you fucking hate everybody. <strong>I fucking hate everyone.</strong></p>

<p>But, no matter how much I want to kill someone, I really feel sad. Why? <em>Come on, that&rsquo;s a stupid question.</em></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m an avid fan of Disney&rsquo;s Penis and Perv, something that sounds like that. I particularly want the scenes where Dr. Doofenshmirtz, the main antagonist, tells his backstory which explains and justifies his present <strong>evil</strong> plans.</p>

<p>Hmm&hellip; So?</p>

<p>Well, I think we all have an intense story behind our bullshit behavior. You&rsquo;ve been bullied during high school? Your parents think you&rsquo;re a big disappointment? We all have this insane traumatic story that make this present us imperfect. Imperfect to be liked by everybody.</p>

<p>And I&rsquo;ve denied that fact for years, thinking that people are just fucking annoying because they are born that way.</p>

<p>Everyone. I&rsquo;m sorry. I&rsquo;m also full of bullshit. I&rsquo;m no different. We are all full of bullshits. You know what I&rsquo;ve realized: I need bullshits in my life. We need bullshits to complete our life.</p>

<p><strong>Happiness is not from a perfect circle of friends. It is from a shitty circle of friends occasionally throwing shits to each other then wiping out each other&rsquo;s shit stains after.</strong></p>

<p>Anyway, I still hate you. But we can talk and have some beer sometime. :)</p>

<p><strong>NOTE: </strong> <em>This post is written after having marathons of The Community Season 1 and 2. The author may or may not be under the influence of the characters portrayed in that fucking series.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nikola Tesla Is A Loser]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2012/12/22/nikola-tesla-is-a-loser/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T17:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2012/12/22/nikola-tesla-is-a-loser</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s almost a year and a half since I started working. Since I started building the foundation of my career. Maybe it&rsquo;s too early, but I just learned a major lesson in life.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t want to brag too much about myself (F*ck it. This is my blog), but I can confidently say that I&rsquo;m a skilled programmer. During college, I programmed a Lexer Generator for our mini compiler project and my professor thought that I just downloaded it. I don&rsquo;t know if the University expects less from students or if what I did is really unbelievable. Once, I got 150/100 score because I taught one of my professor a nifty technique to convert a number string to an integer object. I also have a short debate with another professor about Polymorphism, and made him doubt his knowledge in the said topic. I got exempted from a quiz because I&rsquo;m the only one who answered a challenge question given by a professor &mdash; <em>&ldquo;What is the difference between functional programming and object-oriented programming? And why is there a need for OOP?&rdquo;</em>. I explained to the whole class about the heap and stack, what triggers stack overflow error, how OOP helps prevent stack overflow, how an object is instantiated and other sh*ts. <strong>I&rsquo;m not a cum laude or whatever, I just know my sh*ts</strong>. Well, those are some of the highlights of my pre-work life. Sorry I bragged too much. I didn&rsquo;t mean to.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong><em>&ldquo;You need to be exceptionally good to succeed.&rdquo;</em></strong></p>

<p>My dad keeps telling me that. So after graduation I&rsquo;m confident that I will succeed because I feel that I&rsquo;m exceptionally good. I&rsquo;ll just keep doing my best and all the things will go right. But f*ck it! This is real life.</p>

<p>Nikola Tesla, do you know him? Chances are you don&rsquo;t have any idea who the f*ck is that guy. I can&rsquo;t blame the society for not recognizing this man. Because of the fact that he is a loser. Don&rsquo;t get me wrong please. Tesla is one of my inspirations in life. He is a great scientist. He is exceptionally good in his field. But sadly, <strong>he is a loser in the game of life</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;Tesla: Man Out Of Time&rdquo;</strong>.</p>

<p>Tesla&rsquo;s ideas are really out of this world that people believe that he is way ahead in time. I will not go deeper on this topic but you can just google his name and you will realize how important his contributions are to this modern world. But why is he not famous like Einstein and Edison? Is he really that great? Well, if you are questioning his intellect, I will give you a rabbit, wait until you fall in love with it, then I will put it in a blender, and I will forcefully let you drink that rabbit shake while watching you cry. <a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla">Tesla is great, period</a>.</p>

<p>Do you know that he is considered the major contributor for the development of Alternating Current? As in, AC, the reason why your electric devices are running. Yes, because of Tesla you can watch TV documentaries on how Thomas Edison worked with Direct Current. I can say that Tesla is way more intelligent than our famous hero Edison. But in terms of success, Edison is too far ahead of Tesla. Why? Because <strong>Tesla is just a super geek</strong>. He doesn&rsquo;t know how to market his talent. He doesn&rsquo;t know how to handle competitors. He is not a good businessman. He is just a great scientist while Edison is a superb CEO.</p>

<p>Edison knows how to play the game. I mean he really is a f*cking good player! He publicly demonstrated electrocution of animals using Alternating Current, just to tell the public not to support Tesla&rsquo;s ideas. Edison is a brilliant and dirty businessman. That&rsquo;s why he succeeded. While Tesla ended up selling his patents. It is really an unfair life. Despite of Tesla&rsquo;s greatness he still didn&rsquo;t receive the recognition that he deserves. Just because he didn&rsquo;t play well on this cruel game of life.</p>

<p>Life is a game. Sometimes you really need to play dirty. A cruel world indeed. I thought everything will be okay because of my skills. I thought I can just write great codes and everyone will recognize me. I thought I can just create programs and people will magically have interest in me. I realized, talent is not enough. <strong>A great scientist is different from a great businessman. A skillful programmer is different from a good employee</strong>. I need to participate in this ridiculous game. I need to learn politics. I need to know how to sell myself. I need to learn to fight. This is life&hellip;</p>

<p>This post is really about me. Nikola Tesla is just a bait. I know no one will read this if this is titled <strong>&ldquo;Sadly, Karl Paragua Is A Loser&rdquo;</strong>. Who cares right?</p>

<p>Sorry. That&rsquo;s life. Sometimes you must play dirty to get what you want. Cruel world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Confusing Feeling Called Hate]]></title>
    <link href="http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2012/10/27/the-confusing-feeling-called-hate/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T17:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kbparagua.github.io/blog/2012/10/27/the-confusing-feeling-called-hate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>&ldquo;Everyday, I make sure that I find time to hate people. It&rsquo;s good. It makes me think more about mysteries of life. ohhhh. f</em>ck you!&rdquo;*</p>

<p>A few days ago, my alter ego made that bold tweet. I was confused by that statement, so me and my alter ego had a talk about that sudden brain fart. The conclusion was startling. Nah, enough with the alter ego conspiracy just to sound like this post is something psychological. I just tweeted that because I realized that there is no single day in my life that I haven&rsquo;t killed someone in my mind. Yet I feel so good about it. So I&rsquo;ve reflected.</p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;There is something wrong with the site&rdquo; &mdash;&ndash; How the f*ck will I know what&rsquo;s wrong?! Can you just tell me what&rsquo;s the error!?&ldquo;</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&ldquo;If you have nothing nice to say, don&rsquo;t say anything at all&rdquo;, the wise guys said.</p>

<p>Why? Because negative things will just hurt people? Because hating someone will not contribute to the betterment of the world? Maybe. One thing I learned from all these years is that positive things just make us feel flattered. They feel so good. But sometimes they make us feel complacent. They even go up all the way in your head. They said you&rsquo;re so good at programming, so you subconsciously stopped striving to be the best. They said you&rsquo;re beautiful, so you assumed that almost all boys like you. On the other hand, negative things screw your heart, your dignity, and your self-esteem. It hurts so bad, you can even feel it after a year or so. But then after all of that you became stronger. Everyday you have that overflowing motivation to prove your haters wrong. A friend of mine once told me that people are like springs.<strong> We are like those magnificent spiral things, we need to be pushed down before we can fly high.</strong></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s another interesting and sorta funny thing about hate. Hatred is one of the best foundations of strong friendship. Okay. I&rsquo;m not educated enough to make this stupid assumption. But this is just my observation. It seems that two people develop a strong and deep connection if they hate the same people or things. I think that liking both thing is too shallow to create a spark between two people. And loving both person will just result to unimaginable catastrophe, especially for girls. But hating both thing or person is way much different. Finding someone who hates what you hate is like finding a soul mate. Finally a person who also wants to kill that b*tch.</p>

<p>So I think Dora The Explorer needs to stop saying &ldquo;I like that too&rdquo; all the time! Rather she must ask us what part of the adventure we hate the most and then shout &ldquo;I F*cking hate that too!&rdquo;. That way, she&rsquo;ll have a stronger connection with the kids. If only Dora The Explorer&rsquo;s producer is Seth MacFarlane.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve questioned myself about this constant hate inside me. Am I really just short-tempered? Or there are just too many idiots around me? Or maybe, just another conspiracy, maybe I&rsquo;m a product of a secret twisted government project for creating humanoids to spread negativity nationwide. But my best guess is that my profession molded me to be like this. A short <a href="http://edu.mkrecny.com/thoughts/be-nice-to-programmers" target="_blank">article</a> gave me some ideas about my sick behavior:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Programmer:</strong> When I&rsquo;m not in vim I&rsquo;m in the bug-tracker, a list of negatives. A list of what&rsquo;s broken and needs to be fixed. A list of ways in which I fucked up.</p>

<p><strong>Friend:</strong> Dude, I think you&rsquo;re being a little dramatic. Plus isn&rsquo;t fixing bugs and striking them off that list incredibly satisfying?</p>

<p><strong>Programmer:</strong> Sure it is. There&rsquo;s so much about programming that is incredibly satisfying and empowering. But it doesn&rsquo;t change the fact that, for me, programming builds an acutely negative mindset over time. I&rsquo;m always asking the question &ldquo;what&rsquo;s wrong with this?&rdquo; Positive people are always focusing on &ldquo;what&rsquo;s good about this?&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>So all programmers have a negative mindset? Do all programmers have this habit of hating?
I don&rsquo;t know, but 37Signals said in an article <a href="http://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch05_Start_With_No.php">&ldquo;Start With No&rdquo;</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t be a yes-man
Make each feature work hard to be implemented. Make each feature prove itself and show that it&rsquo;s a survivor. It&rsquo;s like &ldquo;Fight Club.&rdquo; You should only consider features if they&rsquo;re willing to stand on the porch for three days waiting to be let in.</p></blockquote>

<p>Actually, they are not saying that they hate every feature at first. They just don&rsquo;t like them. The idea is like this: <strong>Hate everything at first and let them work hard to be liked</strong>. They are using negativity to choose the best features only. They are using hate to create good things.</p>

<p>I think there are real benefits from hating. What&rsquo;s the force behind Philippines&#8217; People Power Revolution? I don&rsquo;t know, but I&rsquo;m sure those Filipinos hate Marcos. Why did Larry Page and Sergey Brin created Google? Maybe they hate those slow and inaccurate search engines.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m writing this article with no clear idea what I&rsquo;m talking about. I&rsquo;ve no real message in mind. F<em>ck me right? So what&rsquo;s the final verdict for this confusing feeling called hate? Hate is a negative feeling for sure. But we can&rsquo;t deny that it has a huge contribution to the betterment of the world. Love makes the world go round. But hate changes the world dramatically. I&rsquo;m not an evangelist of hate. I just think that hate is a misunderstood feeling. It&rsquo;s okay to hate, just be logical about it. Don&rsquo;t be like those hipsters who hate things because, uhm.. F</em>ck them! What&rsquo;s their reason?!</p>

<p>Everyday make sure you find time to hate. Just don&rsquo;t kill people, especially the clients.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
